# Suboor Khan

Sr.Software Engineer



suboork100@gmail.com



suboorkhan.com



+91-7011879824

# **Relevant Experience**

#### Sr. Software Engineer @ Chetu

Aug 2021 - Present // Noida, India

- Write modern, performant, and robust code for a diverse array of client and internal projects
- Work with a variety of different languages, frameworks, and content management systems such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Vue, NativeScript, Node.js, Ionic, THREE js etc.
- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, clients, and stakeholders on a daily basis.
- Worked with a team of highly experienced engineers to build RPM (Remote Patient Monitoring) based on micro frontend and micro services with CQRS architecture.
- architecture of the application with a super large code base.
- Iterator Design Pattern.

# Software Engineer @ Praxiv

Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 // Gurugram, India

- ▶ Engineered and maintained major features of Whats42nite web app using ES6, Angular, React, Handlebars, Backbone, and CSS
- Manage website development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all crossbrowser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Work closely with programmers and clients to meet project requirements, goals, and desired functionality.
- Developed 42nite web browser purchase Angular app which increase the sales of event tickets to 80%. Created dashboard for pictorial representation of the sales and revenue the app generated by using Chart JS, React JS, Redux and Highcharts.

## Work

## **Anelto Dashboard**

React, Typescript, Redux, Design patterns, Material CSS

Developed and design Anelto dashboard from scratch to display thousands of record of patients and their condition based on how much attention a patient needed and what type of treatment are they going through. Implemented patient reports by using graphs and charts.

## Whats42nite Browser Purchase

Angular, Typescript, RxJS, Firebase

Created an online ticket selling app which increases the sales of tickets by 80%. Integrated payment gateway by using StripeJS, Used Angular-Bootstrap to create the design of the application Demo: https://www.whats42nite.com/pro/views/buyingProcess/#/upcoming-events

#### Starsgyan Dashboard

React JS, Redux, Redux reselect, redux persist

Developed and designed admin panel dashboard for starsgyan Android and iOS application from scratch to keep the records of astrologers and customers and integrated charts and graphs for revenue and payout reports.

#### suboorkhan.com

React, Angular, Typescript, Tailwind, Firebase, RxJS, Redux toolkit

My personal portfolio website to showcase my work and skills, Created my own typescript framework which work as an interceptor between firebase and React/Angular app.

Demo: http://suboorkhan.com/

## About me

Creative Web/Mobile Developer offering 3+ years of experience providing high- impact web solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in designing, developing, and testing multiple web-based applications incorporating a range of technologies. Aspiring to combine broad background with strong technical skills.

# **Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, C++, Swift, PHP

#### **Libraries & Frameworks**

jQuery, React, Redux, Next JS, Node is, Express, Angular, XCode, kubernettes, Docker, RxJS, Ionic, Firebase, Git, Bootstrap

# **Others**

Leadership, Communication, Team Work, Critical Thinking, Teaching

## Education

#### **Bachelor in Computer Application**

2017 - 2019 // Ghaziabad, India Subharti University

#### Intermediate

2014 // Noida, India

National Institute of open schooling

## **Matriculate**

2012 // Ghaziabad, India

Indian Certificate of Secondary Education (ICSE)

# **Interests**

Technology, Travelling, Sc-fi Movies, Netflix, Music